KYLE STEWART

DATA ENGINEER

kylesome@gmail.com

Q 0404 397 106

ABOUT ME

I'm a software developer turned data engineer who is inspired by tough problems. I have over 8 years experience in the ever evolving landscape of software development. I thrive in a collaborative culture where I can enable others to do their best work.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science | University of NSW | 2009 - 2012

Completed courses in algorithms and programming techniques, engineering design, physics, mathematics, databases and computer graphics.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Engineer | Boral | Jan 2019 - present

Creating a modern data stack on Google Cloud Platform. Building a data lake on BigQuery, now with over 20 source systems. Supporting projects including telematics and manufacturing analytics.

- Lead data engineer for Boral's truck telematics solution. Designed and built an end-to-end reporting layer in a multi-cloud environment using AWS IOT, Dataflow and BigQuery.
- Introduced DBT into the data stack, enabling the team transition to a modern ELT workflow.
- Created an orchestration layer using Airflow. Allowing data scientists to reliably schedule pipelines.
- Developed build pipelines to deploy ML models to edge devices at Boral's concrete sites.
- Elevated the team's monitoring capability using logging metrics, Stackdriver and Grafana to ensure SLAs are met.

Platform Engineer | Student.com | Jan 2016 - Oct 2018

Built Python-based microservices running on Kubernetes. Automated deployment and testing as part of a devops culture. Contributed to open source libraries and created content for developers.

- Designed and built domain focused microservices using Python, Namako and RabbitMQ.
- Drove the design and adoption of GraphQL to the platform. Ran workshops to coach the teams on the new design paradigm. Created a gateway service for the frontend teams to query data.
- Contributed to the Nameko open source project. Created content for developers to learn about the framework.
- Migrated the entire platform stack to Kubernetes clusters running in multiple AWS regions.

Web Developer | Student.com | Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

Worked on building and maintaining a high traffic volume site localised in 18 languages. Contributed to several key product features including search, room pricing and the booking system.

- Created backend services to power the search page using ElasticSearch.
- Integrated features with Fastly edge cache to improve load times for images and content.
- Drove the adoption of modern JS bundling techniques into the build pipeline using Webpack.
- Built dashboards using Kibana to monitor metrics such as error rates.

Software engineer | My Mate Your Date | Dec 2013 - Dec 2014

My Mate Your Date is a matchmaking startup aimed at finding dates through friends. I wore many hats as part of a small, tightly knit team. Delivering the product from initial launch to UK expansion.

- Built a graph database of social connection data using Neo4J to power the matching engine.
- Worked with MVC patterns and frameworks to develop the application backend with Laravel.
- Built integrations with 3rd party payment APIs such as Stripe.
- Reported directly to the CEO. Breaking down higher level goals into tangible development tasks.

Web developer | BlueArc Group | Feb 2013 - Oct 2013

Consulted as a web developer. Creating websites for local government and banking institutions. Helping brands enter the e-commerce space.

- Developed content heavy websites using Sitecore and Kentico CMS technologies.
- · Worked on concurrent projects and adhered to tight deadlines in a digital agency environment.

VOLUNTEERING

1st year camp tutor | UNSW Computer Science and Engineering Society

Tutor and supervisor for students. Helping organise activities for 1st year students to have fun while learning some computer science concepts and meeting fellow classmates.

Open Day volunteer | UNSW

Informing prospective students about computer science and engineering courses. Answering questions about university life. Helping set up stalls.

Surf Live Saver | Lennox Head Surf Life Saving Club

Volunteer surf life saver doing patrols on the weekends to keep people safe on the beach. Duties included setting up flags, treating acute injuries and keeping swimmers out of rips.

REFERENCES

Referee details available upon request.